PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- So, we've seen two ways
to calculate in-betweens:
linear interpolation and Bézier curves.
Now let's get into the math behind them.
We're gonna build on
some of what we learned
in the environment modeling lesson,
so if you need to review,
click on this link.
Let's start with the simpler
version, linear interpolation.
Let's focus on this segment.
We know the value of y at frame 4 is 750
and the value at frame 8 is 190,
but what's the value of
y at frame 5, 6, or 7?
The picture tells us
that y can be represented
as a linear function of x,
where x is the frame number.
Linear functions can be written
in slope-intercept form:
y = mx + b,
where m is the slope and
b is the y-intercept.
Now we don't know the slope
and intercept directly,
but we do have two points on the line,
which is enough information
to calculate them.
Now, once we have m and b,
we can figure out y for any frame.
Try out this next exercise
to test your understanding
of linear interpolation using
the slope-intercept form. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox