PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
In Pixar BOX
We met a linear interpolation.
Now we'll smooth movements using Bezier curves.
Shape each portion of the curve determine the 4 points.
So how do you write an equation
which will give us a gentle curve on the basis of these points?
You might remember a similar problem with a lesson about modeling environment.
We tried to make curved blades of grass.
By three points określaliśmy parabolic curve
by  string art .
Recall this method.
Call points: A, B and C.
We also have the  t
determining the location of a point on the section.
First, we calculate the point on AB
using the concept of weighted average.
It's a different kind of linear interpolation,
but instead of the directional pattern
we use the model parameter.
The  t  tells you how far we stretch.
When  t  rises from 0 to 1,
our new point, call it Q,
moves from A to B.
Let's do the same for the second section.
Calculate the R point between B and C.
Finally, we apply the same method to QR
to calculate the P - a point on our average.
When  t  rises from 0 to 1,
P draws a gentle curve.
You can consider this method to be repeated linear interpolation
because Q, R and P are calculated using a linear function of the  t .
The method of repeated linear interpolation algorithm is called de Casteljau.
Paul de Casteljau discovered this pattern a few years before Pierre Bezier
but he could not publish it before.
We have seen how to use the algorithm de Casteljau,
to form a smooth curve from three points.
The animation control curve using four points.
Take a piece of paper and a pencil and try to come up,
how to get smooth curve with four points instead of three.  aimozhen.com/pixarinabox