PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Now that we've seen how Bézier curves
behave geometrically, let's take a look at the algebra
starting with a three-point polygon.
As before, we construct a point Q
using linear interpolation,
that is a weighted average on the line segment AB.
Algebraically, Q can be written as
Q = (1-t)A + tB
Next we construct a point R on the line segment BC,
which means that R can be written as
R = (1-t)B + tC
Finally we connect Q and R,
and do one final linear interpolation
to get P, out point on the curve.
P = (1-t)Q + tR
From this last equation,
it kinda look like P is degree 1 in t.
But the first two equations also depend on t.
So let's substitute the first two equations into the third
to get this combined expression.
Multiplying out the terms and collecting,
I can rewrite P as
P = (1-t)2*A + 2t(1-t)B +t2*C.
All those squared terms show us
that P is actually a degree 2 polynomial.
Interesting, a three-point polygon
leads to a degree 2 polynomial.
Thar kinda makes sense because we did two stages
of linear interpolation.
In the first stage we computed Q and R
and in the second stage we computed P.
Now, what happens to the degree
if we start with a four-point polygon?
Can you guess?
In the first stage, I compute three points
using linear interpolation.
In the second stage, I compute two points,
and in the third stage, I compute one point.
Since I have three stages,
the resulting curve will be degree 3.
That means a four-point polygon results in a degree 3 curve.
You can generalize deCastlejau's algorithm
to start with five, six, or any number of points.
The rule is, if we start with n points,
you get a polynomial of degree n-1.
Pretty neat.
And congratulations on finishing this lesson.
If you're feeling particularly bold,
try your hand at the following bonus challenge. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox