PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
yeah, so, early, early on - I grew up
my dad didn't believe in having a TV in the house
because he didn't want me to waste my time
watching Saturday-morning cartoons
But I love cartoons!
The penmanship and craftsmanship was incredible
So that was the inspiration
and it also became entertainment for me
So I just love to just, you know
spend my time drawing.
&gt; Do you have any examples that we can-
Do you have any pictures or anything
of that early artwork?
&gt; I could! Yeah, I have artwork at home
that I can dig up and that's
you know, I'll be embarrassed to show.
But I'll show it regardless,
'cause you're all my friends out there.
No, art is one of those things
you all start from a place of being-
feeling sensitive about it,
but you just keep doing it, and you enjoy it
and you get better at it
One of those things that fulfills itself.
Oh! I- I built my own computer
when I was about 12 or 13.
Australia was going to dominate
the computer industry with a computer
called the Microbee, so I went ahead and
made this Microbee, and then
Because I could program,
I could actually create characters from it
So one of the big gaming systems back then
was called Aliens, so one of the first programs
I created was these aliens
going across the screen
and you could shoot 'em, and we used a thing
called aimozhen.com/pixarinabox