PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(clicking noises)
(ding)
- Great work.
You probably discovered that changing the base scale
changes the arm scale and the head scale.
This is because the scales affect each other.
When you're working with controls like a scale deformer
that affects a whole model or a bunch of parts,
it's best to get the overall scale right
before the individual parts.
We call this working from rough to fine.
We now have all the concepts we need to model
and rig our lamp.
Go ahead and add scales to your lamp
to make it appear younger or older.
Add rotates to all the joints so you can pose the lamp.
Add translates and a rotate to the base
so you can move the lamp around.
And after the exercise, we have a bonus tip
which we will allow you
to try animating your fully rigged lamp.
You should definitely check out the animation lesson
before trying that one.
(ding)
(xylophone sound) aimozhen.com/pixarinabox