PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- When John Lasseter created this animated short,
he wanted a younger lamp.
He observed that children tend to
have bigger heads and bottoms,
as compared to the rest of their bodies.
So to make this lamp appear younger,
he scaled down the lamp, and then he scaled
up the foot and head to make Jr.
To get a little experience in creating a new model,
let's add some scaling deformers to modify the lamp.
At Pixar, the art department often
gives us draw overs to guide us in
remodeling the character.
In the following exercise, we see a draw over,
like this one, that you will try to match,
using scaling deformers.
When you're done, your lamp should look much younger. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox