PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- We can express so much
emotion through our bodies.
But I really love using rigging to
make expressive faces.
It is fascinating to learn about how
faces display emotions or ideas.
There's so much detail
in every expression.
In our next exercise, we're
gonna rig a snowman face.
And we need some new deformers to do that.
First, let's add a direction scale.
A directional scale allows us to
scale in just one direction.
If you scale the hat using Scale Y,
you'll get a taller hate
that looks like a top hat.
If you scale the face with Scale X,
you will get a wider face.
You also need shear deformers.
Shear deformers are similar
to directional scales,
in the sense that they work
in a specific direction.
We also have our set of rotates,
and translates, and scales,
that we already used.
Just as before, you
should work rough to fine,
with retaining the head to begin with.
And then, translating
and rotating the hat.
Remember, the order of
your deformers matters,
to test your controls as you work.
When you finish rigging the head,
move on to the next lesson where
you'll learn to write code
to make your own character. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox