PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(footsteps)
- We're on our way to the art department,
but we can't show you much of it
because everything there is super secret.
- In the previous video, we saw
how patterns were created to texture
the dinosaur, Arlo, for the
movie The Good Dinosaur.
In this lesson, it will be your turn
to make some convincing dinosaur skin
using patterns, colors, and randomness.
- (Tall Woman) We're
going to introduce you
to some techniques used
here at Pixar to do this.
- (Blonde Woman) Such as voronoi diagrams.
- (Tall Woman) And how we use randomness
to make it look more organic.
- (Blonde Woman) By the end of this lesson
you'll be ready to make
your own dino skin.
- And no matter what we're building,
it all starts with a shading packet.
- And the shading packet comes
from one of the artists in the
art department such as Tia.
(knocking)
- Hi!
- Hey.
- How are you guys?
- Great.
- Good, I have a present for you.
The dino leg shader packet.
There's a few pieces here for you.
Some reference, some color specs,
and some real reference.
Those are for the claws.
I don't have all the answers.
I'm leaving it up to
you guys to do the rest.
I've got to go run and teach a class,
so can I leave this with you?
And you're welcome to use my office.
Have a blast.
- Great.
- Thank you.
- Thank you! Bye.
- The shading packet is a collection
of drawings and images that will guide us
through the process of
creating our dino skin.
- (Blonde Woman) It all begins on paper
because it's much faster
to iterate that way.
- (Tall Woman) Shading
packets also contain
reference photographs like this cactus,
which is a real-life approximation
of the look and feel we're going for.
- (Blonde Woman) This is a wonderful
inspiration for the
scales of our dinosaur,
but it's just a starting point.
- (Tall Woman) Let's
examine these drawings
a little more closely and see what kind
of things Tia has identified.
- (Blonde Woman) First notice there are
a number of scales of
varying sizes sticking out,
or extruding from the skin.
We'll need to figure
out how to build these.
- (Tall Woman) Also notice
the scales vary in size,
some bigger and some smaller.
The bigger scales
correspond to rigid areas,
such as the middle of the leg.
Smaller scales are found
in areas near the claws,
which is an area that
is much more flexible.
- (Blonde Woman) Aside from the size,
position, and shape of the scales
we also have to start
thinking about color.
- (Tall Woman) Notice she wants each scale
to vary in color and a reminder to make
the skin beneath the
scales a different color.
- (Blonde Woman) The final touch
is to pay attention to different kinds
of random variations we'll need.
For example, some scales
extrude more than the others.
Plus, the position and size
of the scale should vary as well.
So there's lots of
variation going on here.
- (Tall Woman) Now it's your turn
to examine the shading packet.
- Once you're comfortable
studying shading packets,
we'll get to work creating
the patterns in the computer. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox