PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Um, I grew up taking
art classes every week,
uh, on Saturdays in addition
to my school art classes.
So, I did a lot of drawing and painting,
and as I got older I
specialized a little bit more
in like photography and design work.
I think I've just always like puzzles,
and problems to solve,
and you know, it's so logical.
It just, it fits together,
and so, uh, I think that's
why I always liked math.
There is an answer.
You can find the answer and solve it.
Well, I really didn't know that a job
like the job I have at Pixar would exist
when I was in college.
I studied graphic design
and I really loved that.
And then, when I was almost
finished with undergrad,
I stumbled upon an animation
studio in Columbus, Ohio
that was working on the movie Space Jam.
And the idea that somebody in my hometown
was working on a movie
was just amazing to me.
So, I showed up one day at their door,
literally knocked on the door,
and just tried to get an internship.
And people, nobody knew
what to make of me.
They were like who are you?
Do you have an appointment?
And I was like no, I just
really want to work here,
and um, because I was
really eager and excited,
and they were impressed
that I was looking for
a summer job in January,
the year before, I got a summer job.
So I worked at that
studio which was called
Character Builders in
Columbus, Ohio for ten years.
And I worked on bunch of
TV animation, uh, projects.
As that was happening,
3D animation was becoming
more and more popular,
and kind of more and more awesome,
and I really didn't
know that much about it.
And I was lucky in my second
or third year in grad school,
there were recruiters from
Pixar that came to my program,
which was a CAD at the highest university,
and I was offered a
technical director residency.
So when I finished my Master's degree,
I came to Pixar as a resident,
and I've been here ever since.
Um, I have been in shading and grooming.
I started here on day and night,
and um, started shading with props,
uh, characters, and some set pieces.
And I also started
grooming on that project.
And then I worked on several features
and shorts as a groomer,
and a character shading artist.
- [Interviewer] What does a groomer do?
- Groomers put hair and fur on things,
so if you imagine, you know,
if you give a dog a bath,
and all of a sudden it's
much, much skinnier?
The same happens with our animal models.
The bodies are much smaller,
and we have to put the hair on
to get the right silhouettes,
so grooming sometimes is a cross
between modeling and shading.
It's sort of like modeling,
because you're worried about
the silhouette of the character
and making their shape look correct,
but it's also like shading
in that you're responsible
for the surface quality of the object.
Um, one of my favorites was
Art from Monster's University.
He was a really fun challenge
because he's just like an arch
and he flips around all different ways,
so there are a lot of rigging challenges,
um, to get him to move the correct way.
And then to keep the hair looking right
with the little points
in all the right places.
That was a really fun one to work on.
Make as much work as you can.
Find as many people to hang
out with that make work
that you think is inspiring as you can.
Surround yourself with people
who are better than you,
because they'll make you
better at what you do. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox