PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- I grew up in Uruguay.
A little country between
Brazil and Argentina.
There's about three million
people in the country.
I did not have any experience. (laughs)
I came straight from school.
I have a duel degree in
electrical engineering
and fine arts.
I am kind of right brain,
left brain, kind of person.
I really like arts and I
really like engineering,
and I found out there was a career
that you can combine both,
so I thought that was great.
And then I just happen to
interview with Ed Catmull,
was the president at the time.
I just thought it would be
great to meet one of the people
that had written some of
the stuff in my books.
And so I went for the
interview and I got the job.
When I went to college,
I was really interested in sculpting.
That was my main path.
I worked a lot in clay, I worked on paper,
I worked on wire.
At the end of my career I started doing
a little bit of computer
graphics, but not a lot.
So when I came to Pixar,
of course I wanted to be an animator,
but the people that know best (laughs)
decided that probably a
technical director career
would be best for me, given that I had
the technical orientation
and the art, as well.
But the first one I did was
lighting TD on Geri's Game.
- [Interviewer] What do lighters do?
Lighting TDs?
- Lighting TD.
So if you can imagine a theater
and putting up the lights
wherever you want the character
to be looking pretty for the camera,
that's basically what lighting TDs do.
We are trying to emphasize the story
and what we want to get across,
and then make our things
look pretty, or scary,
or whatever they need to
be as part of the story.
And then I started working in shading.
For shading, I did a lot of
prop shading, I did set shading,
and recently I've been doing
a lot more character shading.
And I also worked as a lead shading artist
for The Good Dinosaur.
Shading is basically creating
the material qualities
as you see in objects.
So when the models come to us,
they're basically just white plastic,
and we make them look the way
that they're supposed to look.
So if you have a piece of
wood, you want to figure out
what kind of pattern you want on the wood,
or how does the light
interact with the material.
If there's certain bumpiness to it,
if it's reflective, if it feels smooth,
or if the light goes into
the wood a little bit
and bounces around and comes off.
So there's a lot of math involved
into trying to figure
out that kind of system,
and how does the illumination
interact with the material,
and how do you perceive it.
And a lot of the times it's really funny
because the idea that you have mentally
of what the object should look like
is actually really
different from what you want
to put on the screen.
Sometimes I'm driving around
and I'll see a cloud on the sky
and I'll think to myself,
if I make that cloud
on the computer it will
look completely wrong,
and people would not believe it's a cloud.
But it's up there, it's in the sky.
So a lot of times you have to figure out
what our idea of the cloud is,
versus what the cloud really is.
I just like, for me cooking is almost
like a little bit of a travel experience.
It's an adventure.
So I tend to do really strange dishes
from what we're used to having.
Love using new ingredients and
stuff that I can't pronounce,
and just go for it.
Don't be afraid to say
you don't know something
because that's the only way you can learn.
Don't be afraid to make mistakes
because that's the only way we learn.
And just keep shooting
for what you want to be,
what you're passionate about.
That's really what's important
because that's what will
make you happy in the future,
just working for your passion. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox