PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Now that we're comfortable with
the geometry of our cells
let's flesh out some details.
Let's take a closer look
at the shading packet.
- [Red Haired Woman] Notice
each cell contains some skin
around the edge with the scale
sticking out in the middle.
- [Brunette Woman] We need
to decide how far it is
between the edge of the cell
and the start of a scale.
This gap will expose the skin
that the scales are growing out of.
- [Red Haired Woman] In
our program we can do this
with this parameter called scale size.
If we maximize the scale size
it covers all the skin which looks wrong.
So we need to pull it back slightly
to get the gap we need.
- [Brunette Woman] That looks
nice but notice the distance
between the scales is the same everywhere.
- [Red Haired Woman] Right,
that's not very natural.
We've added a control here to vary
the distance between scale edges.
- [Brunette Woman] That look perfect.
Next, we need to make the scales look
like they're extruding,
sticking out from the skin.
- [Red Haired Woman] In our
program we can control how far
they stick out with
this extrude parameter.
- Now we have a model for our dino-skin
that we can start shading.
- Let's take a look at the shading packet
and examine the color notes.
- [Brunette Woman] It says
each scale should have
a slightly different color
and the skin should be
darker and leathery.
- [Red Haired Woman] So we'll
add some color controls here.
One for the skin and one for scales.
- [Brunette Woman] To pull this off
we have a really cool trick.
We define a range of colors
from the smallest scale, here,
to the largest scale, here.
- [Red Haired Woman] And now
our program will color each
scale based on its size.
So the smaller scales will
look more like this color,
and the larger scales will
look more like this color.
And all of the other scales
will be somewhere in between.
- [Brunette Woman] That's very cool.
It saves us time because we don't have
to define the color of
each scale individually.
- [Red Haired Woman] Now,
see how the color varies
very naturally according
to the scale size.
- [Brunette Woman] We also
added a preview button
to give us a rough idea on
how our pattern will look.
- Neat. Okay, now it's your turn to use
all these ideas to create
your own dino-skin.
- And in the final exercise we can
use all the tools we
introduced in this lesson.
- And when you're happy with your creation
move onto the next lesson where we'll
be adding microscopic level detail.
This should really make
our dino leg look great.
Do you always have a model
first and then start shading?
- Most of the time we have the model first
and then we realize that
we need something that has
a little bit of a different geometry
and we wanna add certain details
in certain areas of the model.
So sometimes we end up changing the model
after shading has already started. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox