PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Hi. I'm Alonso Martinez and I'm a Character modeler
here at Pixar Animation Studios,
and that means that I create the virtual characters
that the animators use to bring our characters to life.
And if I do my job right that means that
not only will people believe that they're real,
but also they'll become personal friends.
Right now I'm standing at the Pixar Art Gallery
and this place is dedicated to celebrate
all of the hard work
that goes into making these movies great.
It's important for all departments here at Pixar
to help with the story telling.
And for the character department,
when we design our characters,
we tell story through the shapes of our characters.
One of my favorite examples is from the movie Up,
and that's because Carl is designed like a box
and that's because he's jailed in with all of the emotions
from the hard times that he's had in life.
But Russell is shaped like an egg.
Both of these are symbols for who these characters are.
To create great characters like these,
we need to make tools that are easy
for artists to create those shapes
that we were talking about.
And also, at the same time, for them to be efficient
for the computer to be able to deal with all of that data.
And that's the topic for this lesson.
Stick around for more.
In the Environment Modeling Lesson
we saw how to describe blades of grass using parabolas,
but parabolas are just not good enough
to describe the expressiveness of characters.
For example, here's a sculpture of Geri's hand
from Geri's Game.
To describe complex surfaces like this,
that's where subdivision comes in.
And as we saw in the previous video,
subdivision is extremely expressive.
In the first part of the lesson
we'll be looking more closely at how subdivision
can be used to create complex shapes.
And then in part two, we'll dive more deeply
into the mathematics of subdivision.
Most of the mathematics we use here at Pixar
have been around for hundreds or thousands of years,
but subdivision is different.
It was actually only invented about 40 years ago
and is still an active area of mathematical research.
The skins of our characters live in three dimensional space,
but for now, we're going to look at curves
in two dimensions.
Starting with a four-point polygon,
we add more points by Splitting,
that is, by adding mid-points to the edges.
I can make it smoother by moving each point
from where it is now,
to the mid-point of its right neighbor.
We call this, the Averaging step.
By repeatedly Splitting and Averaging,
we create a series of increasingly smoother curves.
Now, imagine that you're an artist at Pixar
and you've been asked to create a shape like this one.
Using this next interactive,
see how close you can get. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox