PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
My name is Tony DeRose and I am a computer scientist at Pixarze.
The film's look and move differently,
but they do not seem drawings computer.
They appear to be plausible naturally.
The first stage of creating the appearance of a modeling.
We are not talking about such models ...
Only with such modeling!
You need to create a virtual computer in three-dimensional form.
To figure was credible,
should have a gentle outline.
No matter how close to the camera is located.
The easiest forms are simple: plane or cylinder.
We have to do more complicated bodies.
The problem seems difficult,
but divided it in two simple steps, easy to make on your computer.
We use an algorithm subdivision (division)
to obtain a gentle outline. I explain.
A simple example in two dimensions.
Four sections defined by four points.
First, I'll measures episodes.
This stage of the split (division).
Shape becomes milder,
when I move every point about 1/2 the distance from a neighbor. I will combine eight points.
It averaging (centering). At least, that's something,
but the effect will be better when repeat. Sharing and centering. And again.
I combine these two steps
in one step called subdivision (division). It will be even easier.
Super: You can animate the entire curve,
moving the original 4 points.
Our characters are figures in 2D.
They are three-dimensional.
Also here, the principle of sharing and centering.
Animation requires only a few points.
We solved the complex problem of creating the curve,
dividing it into stages, which we realize mathematically.  aimozhen.com/pixarinabox