PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- One of the cool things about
splitting and averaging is
that it's pretty easy to program.
So, you just need to find the midpoint,
which is just averaging coordinates.
This makes it pretty easy
for the people that write our software
to create intuitive tools for artists,
like myself, to create characters.
Kinda like you used on the smiley face.
In this next version of the interactive,
we've replaced the split
and average buttons
with a single button, called "Subdivide".
Clicking it simply does
split followed by average.
Focus your attention on
this region of the curve.
Now, let's extend these lines
until they hit the control polygon.
Hmm. Doesn't this look, suspiciously,
like the string art construction
we saw in the parabolic arcs?
Now, watch what happens
when I subdivide again.
The string art pattern
continues to emerge.
Now, every time you hit subdivide,
you get twice as many strings.
And that means that the curve
that we're creating is a
parabolic arc in this region.
And there's another
parabolic arc over here
and over here and over here.
But, magically, these
four arcs are smoothly
blending from one to another.
I think that's just so cool.
As someone interested in mathematics,
this is the kind of surprise
that I find exciting.
This next exercise will test
how well you understand this concept. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox