PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- [Instructor] How many
different colors can you see?
Feels like an endless possibility.
Impossible to count them all, right?
Well, if we want to
represent colors digitally,
we have to find a way of counting color.
That is, for any given shade you can see,
we need to give it a unique
number or an address.
Because numbers are something
both humans and machines can agree on.
One simple way we could do this is
to give a percentage for each color value.
We call this an RGB triple.
For example, 100% red plus 100% green
plus 100% blue is white.
0% red, 0% green, 0% blue is black.
Whereas, 100% red and 100%
green, but 0% blue, is yellow.
We saw this in lesson one.
Mathematicians love to represent things
geometrically or spatially,
so they came up with the
idea of a color space.
It's quite simple.
Normally, we represent a point
in three dimensional space
using x, y, and z-coordinates, like this.
But, instead, let's rename
the axes red, green, and blue.
And that gives us this color cube.
The key idea is this: every
point within this cube
represents a specific color
a projector or a computer
monitor could create.
So, remember all those colors
you were thinking about?
Well, any specific color you're looking at
will always be a point in this cube.
To help this sink in, we
have a color cube exercise
that you can play with.
Give it a try. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox