PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(springing)
(thudding)
- Now let's return to the
human eye for a moment.
Remember, the human eye is the sensor
which light must pass
through to be perceived.
So we need to understand the limit
of the human visual system.
In the 1920s, experiments were done
to map the color space
perceivable by humans.
From purple, all the
way around the rainbow,
to this red, this defines all colors
of a single wavelength.
These are known as spectral colors,
and inside this region,
we have all combinations
of those pure colors.
Scientists plotted the limit
of the pure colors we can perceive.
Notice it takes this funny looking shape.
One reason this shape is useful is
something called perceptual uniformity.
That's a fancy way of saying
that we can find the
mixture of two colors,
such as this red and this green,
by simply looking at the
midpoint of them, right here.
It's known as the CIE
chromaticity diagram.
CIE refers to the scientific group
that published the findings.
Compare this to the hue
saturation color wheel,
which is not perceptually uniform.
Pure red is here, pure green is here,
but the middle of these two points is
not pure yellow at all,
it's a very desaturated yellow.
Okay, let's pause here.
In this next exercise,
we'll challenge you to think more
about this CIE chromaticity diagram,
and perceptual uniformity. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox