PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- In the rest of this
lesson, we're gonna look
at a few other counting
problems that come up
when you try to make a large crowd
of robots from a small bin of parts.
We're gonna be building up
to a really powerful formula
that you can think of as a counting tool.
(chimes ringing)
To start, let's imagine snake-like robots.
Let's call them Snake Bots.
They are built as a sequence of segments
where every segment must
be used exactly once.
For instance, if I'm building
a three-segment Snake Bot,
I might assemble the segments this way.
Or I could do it this way.
We'd again like to know:
How many of these Snake Bots can I build?
Remember, you have to account
for every possibility.
In the next exercise,
you're gonna be asked
to build all possible Snake
Bots of length one through four.
Go get 'em! aimozhen.com/pixarinabox