PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Great job completing the last tutorial!
You made both the director and the producer very happy.
Sometimes our directors change their minds when they see
their drawings translated to 3D computer graphics.
In fact, sometimes our directors change their minds a lot,
and we need to be able to adapt to those changes.
So let's say we have a director that wants a robot
with two heads, but each head has to be different.
That is, the director doesn't want a robot
with two copies of the same head.
Now a robot consists of two heads, a body, and arms.
We'd like to know how many of those we can have
if we have H heads, B bodies, and A arms.
We saw that by using a Tree Diagram we could multiply
the number of each kind of part together
to get the total number of combinations.
Well, we have H choices for the first head,
but since the second head has to be different,
we only have H minus one choices for the second head.
As before, we have B choices for bodies
and A choices for arms, for a total
of H times H minus one
times B times A combinations.
So it's all about multiplying together
all the choices you have at each stage.
Mathematicians make up words for everything.
They use the word combinatorics
to refer to this type of counting.
The next exercise will give you a chance
to practice with other combinations. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox