PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Good work!
I left you with this question:
Why are there exactly six combinations of each cast
when you select three actors from a group of four?
To get a feeling for what's up,
let's look at the first two boxes.
Notice that in the first cast, or box,
we have all possible orderings of A, B, and C.
Mathematicians call each of these orderings a permutation.
Now, the number of permutations is represented
by the number of rows in each box.
The same is true in the second cast involving A, B, and D.
How many orderings, or permutations,
are there of three things?
We saw earlier that there are three
factorial, or six permutations.
Bingo! That's it!
To keep order for mattering, we need to take
the total number of combinations where order does matter
and divide that by all the possible permutations.
So when choosing three actors from four actors total,
we can write our calculation as
four times three times two
over three factorial, which equals four.
Let's do another example and figure out how many casts
we can form with three actors from a pool of six actors.
In this case, there would be six times five times four.
We then have to again divide by three factorial
to keep the order from mattering,
leaving six times five times four
over three factorial, which equals 20.
So there are 20 different casts in this case.
Use the next exercise to get some practice
with some other examples.
And perhaps you'll recognize our good friend
M-O in the cast. (robotic sounds) aimozhen.com/pixarinabox