PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- To see how to put the diagrams together,
let's go back to the example where we had
just two kinds of parts, heads and bodies.
Suppose I pick, umm,
this head and this body.
Or, I can pick this body, or this one,
let's finish off all the possibilities.
Notice that the bottom of the diagram
has six combinations as before.
And the diagram, hopefully, makes it clear
that we have two choices of
heads and for each of those,
we have three choices of bodies.
Or, two times three combinations.
Use the next interactive to figure out
what the diagram would look
like if there were a different
number of heads and a
different number of bodies.
(squeak, boing, squeak, squeak, squeak) aimozhen.com/pixarinabox