PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Great work, but suppose the director decides
that we need robots made up of a little more variety
and now, we need three kinds of parts;
heads, bodies, and arms.
When there are three parts to combine,
the table doesn't work anymore.
We need some other way to think about all the different ways
that three parts can be combined.
It would be even better if we can think of a way that works
for two, or three, or four, or even more kinds of parts.
When I first start trying to solve a new problem,
I like to break that problem down
into a bunch of smaller parts that are easier to solve.
In this case, counting the number of robots made
from two heads and three bodies.
I can illustrate the two ways of selecting a head
using a picture like this.
And, I can illustrate the three ways of selecting a body
The problem with these picture so far is, they make it look
like there are only five possible combinations.
Before moving on to the next video,
see if you can combine these two diagrams
to show that there are six different combinations of robots. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox