PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
In the previous clip and exercise, we saw a table
can easily monitor various
robots, each has a head
and one body.
Each of these robots combination.
Constantly we are dealing with combinations.
For example, when we in the morning
and choose your top and bottoms.
This is also combining.
Since each box in the table corresponds
a different combination, just count
cells but do not have to be one by one.
This is because the number of cells in tabiltsata
equals the number of rows multiplied by the number of columns.
With two heads and three bodies
there are two three, i.e. six combinations.
With three heads and four bodies
we have three in four, ie twelve combinations.
The following exercise will allow
to try other combinations.  aimozhen.com/pixarinabox