PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Hi, my name is Lou Hamou-Lhadj.
I'm a Character TD here at Pixar.
- Hi, I'm Jacob Speirs, I'm
also a Character TD at Pixar.
- [Lou] We started here at
Pixar on WALL-E as interns
and our task was to make a
huge cast of background robots.
- Today's lesson is going
to be about how to create
a huge crowd of robots using
only a few simple parts.
(mechanical clicks)
- I wanna take WALL-E from a world
where there's no robots anymore
and it's just him to a world
where there's tons of them.
I just like that contrast
and suddenly making him feel
like he was alone in a crowd.
- We're trying to create a
world where robots do every task
that you would want done.
What we did first was
to look at cruise ships.
We got a list of every
single job on a cruise ship
and then went through
and tried to think of
the robotic equivalent of that job
and it became apparent quickly
that that was more robots
than we would ever be able
to build in one lifetime.
- So as interns, Jacob and I
had the task of making this
huge cast of robots, but we
didn't want to design each
individual one specifically.
- Right, so luckily there
was an animator, Angus,
and he had a great idea about
how to approach the process.
- I'm a huge Lego fan and I really wanted
the background characters
to be the best they could be
and I figured if we
designed a modular system
that would allow for us to add
and subtract different parts
onto the character for
the background characters
then we could kinda
make whatever we needed
and it would all feel like the same world.
- [Lou] Doing it this way, modularly,
meant we could build 10
heads, 10 arms, and 10 bodies
and though we'd only built 30 pieces
we could make a thousand
different combinations.
- Yeah, and there's actually
a branch of mathematics
about that sort of thing,
counting and combinations
and it's called combinatorics.
(mechanical noises)
- Combinatorics is actually
what your lesson today
is gonna be about.
We're gonna start with a few small pieces
and build a huge cast of
robots just like we did. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox