PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Hi, I'm Fran Kalal.
I'm a cloth and sim technical director
at Pixar Animation Studios.
That means I get to take what I know about art and design
and make outfits, and what I know
about math and physics to make them move.
I'm here today to talk to you about crowds
like the large one behind me.
Except that the one behind me is physical,
and the ones we need to make
for our films are virtual.
That means they exist only on the computer.
We saw in the last video how lots of robots were made
using only a few parts through
the use of combinatorics.
So follow me to learn more about
what combinatorics is and how we use it at Pixar.
To understand how many robots we can make
from a bin of parts, let's start with an example
where a robot has one head and one body.
And I've got two different heads to choose from
and three different bodies.
So I can take this head with this body,
or this same head with this body,
and that's already two different robots.
And clearly I can make a whole lot more.
A great way to keep track of this is with a table
where I'm going to place the heads along the columns
and the bodies along the rows.
This cell means put this head on this body.
There are six cells on the table,
so there are six different robots
even though we only have five different parts.
This is a great example of the fact
that finding a good way to think about a problem
makes it easier to solve.
How many robots could you make
if there were different numbers of heads and bodies?
You can explore that question in the next exercise. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox