PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- So far our discussion has been largely visual
and geometric and that's good because
that's how our artists think.
But at   Pixar we also have to create
computer programs and computers think best
in terms of numbers, equations, and algebra.
So somehow we have to bridge these two worlds.
The worlds of images and geometry
and the world of algebra, numbers, and equations.
In fact, this bridge between these two worlds
was one of the things that really drew me
into computer graphics in the first place.
I find it really fascinating, how the algebra
and the geometry conspire to create beautiful art.
So what we're going to do is develop a formula that will
allow us to compute points exactly on the parabola.
And that formula will allow us to write computer programs
like this one, that will be able to draw the parabola
without ever having to draw any of the string art lines.
Our first step in the search of that formula
is to generalize the idea of averaging or midpoints
to the idea of weighted averages.
So, let's look at our line segment AB again
but instead of wanting to compute the midpoint
suppose I want to compute a point M, say
right about here, that weights B twice as heavily as A.
There isn't anything particularly special
about weighting B twice as heavily as A
it's just a simple non-midpoint example.
So, the algebra would say that M
is one copy of A plus two copies of B
and then I have to divide by three
for this to be a proper average.
And I can write that a little bit simpler
as A plus two B over three.
And one final form is 1/3 A, 'cause there's
an implicit one here in front of the A
and there's a 2/3 in front of the B, so 2/3 B.
And notice that this 1/3 plus this 2/3 add to one.
And that's another way of saying
that this is a proper average.
So that's the algebra, let's take a look at the geometry.
Well, the geometry says that this length here, AM
is going to be in proportion 2/3 to this length here, MB
which is going to be in proportion 1/3.
Now, notice that the algebra says that the 2/3
sticks to the B, but the geometry says
that the 2/3 is opposite the B.
And that looks a little bit strange at first
but if you think about it, it kind of makes sense
because if there was a big weight in front of B
you'd expect this point to be very close to B.
Okay, well we can generalize this even further and let me
replace a 2/3 here with an arbitrary fraction, call it t.
So the t is going to stick to the B in the algebra
and now for this to be a proper average
I need to put something in front of A
so that something plus t is equal to one.
Well, something that when added to t is one
is a fraction one minus t.
So my expression now is 1 minus t times A plus t times B.
That's the algebra of this generalized situation.
The geometry is that this 2/3 gets replaced
with a t and this 1/3 gets replaced with a one minus t.
So let's get some feeling for this
idea by using this interactive.
So here I've got a line segment that I can drag around
and you can see the coordinates of A
and the coordinates of B and right now it's initialized
so that the point I'm computing is at the midpoint.
So I would have halves in front of each A and B.
But now I can slide this point around anywhere I like
along this line and that corresponds
to just changing the value of t.
So different values of t give me
different positions along the line.
In the next couple of exercises
you'll have an opportunity to get some experience
with the idea of weighted averages.
(arrow flies and hits target) aimozhen.com/pixarinabox