PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- We're ready for step two in our search
for the elusive formula of how to compute
a point exactly on a parabola.
To gain some intuition, let's go back
to the interactive that we used to kick this all off.
So here's my string art construction with a bunch of lines.
And now, let me cycle through the lines one at a time,
highlighted here in magenta.
So there's one of them, here's another one,
here's another one.
And each of these magenta lines can be described
by some fraction T that names that point on the line.
As I wiggle the magenta line back and forth,
notice that it continues to touch the parabola
in exactly one place.
Well if I can develop a formula for where that place is,
that's the formula I'm looking for.
We can see that even more clearly
in this version of the interactive
that you'll be using in a moment
to solve a couple of exercises.
So in this version, I can use this perimeter T
to name which string art line I'm talking about.
And notice that each of the string art lines
touches the parabola in exactly one place.
In the next exercise, you'll be asked to come up with a
hypothesis for where that place is.
And the hypothesis, as a hint,
has something to do with the ratios of these subsegments
that are being created.
And we've color coded those subsegments to give you
an even more of a hint.
So see if you can figure out
what that special relationship is. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox