PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(steps and bouncing)
(switch clicks)
- You should now have some experience
in computing points on parabolas,
using the formulas that we wrote
down in the previous video.
These formulas are based on the hypothesis
that all of these ratios
are in the same proportion,
and that proportion is governed by t.
But now we're gonna prove
that these formulas are actually correct.
So I'm gonna use this version
of the interactive in the proof.
You'll have a chance to experiment
with this interactive in a minute.
And as before, I've got a string art line
that is controlled by a parameter t.
As I wiggle t back and forth,
the string art line
wiggles back and forth.
The method I'm gonna use
to find where the touching point occurs
seems a little bit sneaky at first,
but it's the simplest method I know.
And what I'm gonna do is
introduce another string art line,
this one controlled by a parameter s.
And what I'm gonna do is I'm
gonna write down an expression
for this intersection point
here, this green point.
Now, why would I do that?
Well, the reason is, watch what happens
as s and t get closer and closer together.
So as I make s closer and closer to t,
watch what happens to
this intersection point.
OK, it moves, and it gets closer
and closer to the parabola,
and exactly when s equals t,
that intersection point lies
exactly on the parabola.
So if I can write down a formula
for where that intersection point is,
I can compute exactly where
the touching point occurs.
This is probably a good time
to pause and let you experiment
with this interactive to get some feeling
for what we're about to do algebraically. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox