PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
In Pixar BOX
You already know this and that
of the weighted average for the two and three points.
Let's see what will happen,
When the step of centering with the center points
We replace the weighted average.
Let's go back to the exercise of the division and the curve.
Only now we can change the weight
at the stage of centering.
Ones mean that draw simple average.
I divide the sides, as usual, by proposing their measures.
Now we move the points about half the distance
toward the right-hand neighbor.
Look, what if I change the weight of 2, 2 and 1.
Division
centering
Generalize this to extract the average of the three points.
Look what happens when I change the weight at 1, 2 and 1.
Now I share, as before,
but while centering
each point will move to the designated place weight 2.
The neighbor on the left has a weight of 1
and neighbor on the right - or 1.
This point should move more or less here,
as in the example with the weighted average.
If we divide again and Center, the effect will be the same.
The exercise oswoicie with the concept of weighted divisions. Good luck!  aimozhen.com/pixarinabox