PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(bouncy Pixar theme)
- In the last exercise you probably noticed
that the simulation lacked the natural bounciness of hair.
But what makes something look bouncy anyway?
To make this model bouncy, we need each strand of hair
to expand and contract slightly
when forces are applied to them.
This required a new physical analogy to base our model on,
so we tried springs.
Springs are great because they can change length
when you pull on them,
and to give the hair a little bit of weight,
we add a small weight to the end of the spring.
This is known as a mass spring system.
We can actually draw a mathematical model
to explain what happens when a spring expands and contracts.
The model we use is based on a law developed by Robert Hooke
a 17th century physicist.
Hooke noticed that there are two things to consider
when a spring expands and contracts.
One, if we pull on a spring and it expands,
we will increase its length and it will pull back together.
Two, if the spring contracts, its length will decrease
and it will push apart.
How much a spring pushes and pulls
is known as the spring force.
Robert Hooke was looking for relationship
between the spring force
in the amount the spring contracts or expands.
We call this change in length displacement.
Displacement is defined as the current length
minus the rest length of the spring.
When we stretch a spring, the displacement is positive
and the resulting spring force is negative.
This is known as the pull force.
When we compress a spring, the displacement is negative
and the resulting spring force is positive.
This is called the push force.
So Hooke's observation was quite simple,
he noticed that a larger displacement
results in a larger force,
while a smaller displacement results in a smaller force.
That is, he noticed that the displacement
is proportional to the force.
However, every spring is different,
some take a lot of force to displace,
and some are really easy to displace.
So Robert Hooke introduced the idea of stiffness
to account for how hard it is to displace a given spring.
It is represented with the letter k.
This led Hooke to his final equation
which is known as Hooke's Law.
The spring force is proportional
to a stiffness times the displacement.
Notice that there is a negative sign there,
that's because we want a positive force
when the displacement is negative,
and a negative force when it's positive.
If we plug this equation into the computer
we get this realistic spring behavior.
For Brave, we modeled the horse's hair
using a mass spring system
similar to what we are describing in this tutorial,
nearly 10,000 simulated hairs in total.
In the next exercise you can explore
a simple mass spring system.
You'll be able to adjust the following parameters,
mass of the particle, spring stiffness, k,
and the force of gravity,
and we'll ask you some challenge questions
to make sure you understand the basics of Hooke's Law. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox