PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- So far we've been exploring
what a software engineer
does at Pixar, which is
creating the tools used
in the filmmaking process,
such as a hair simulator
and all the parameters
artists can't control.
The person actually using
these tools in each film
is known at Pixar as
the Technical Director.
To better understand this kind of work,
we've invited Jacob Brooks,
a technical director
who has used hair simulation in our films.
Hey Jacob.
- Hey, how are you?
- Pretty good, so you worked
on Spot for The Good Dinosaur,
- I did, I did, yeah.
- So were the artisticals for Spot's hair?
- Well Spot was one of those
characters that you knew
we wanted to fall in love with right away.
So he had a lot of appeal in him,
but he also kind of
straddles that world of being
in the wilderness so he's gotta
wild and a little unkempt.
So with his hair we were
able to kind of bridge
those two worlds so that you
can still get that feeling
of kind of a matted tangled,
kind of wild animal feel
to him but also get that appeal of like,
just a child that wakes up in the morning
and has adorable bed head.
So it's just super familiar to us.
So for the hair, as far
as the texture goes,
we knew we were gonna have to have strands
that were intertwining
and felt like they hadn't
been washed in a while, not
going towards that gross
factor but something that definitely feels
entangled and unkempt,
but also just kind of hit
those shapes that we knew
that we'd want to just
frame his face nicely and be appealing,
so that he does have that
genuine appeal in the film.
- So how did you model the
hair to meet these artisticals?
- Well before we can
actually simulate the hair
on a character that's moving,
like Spot as he's running
around in the film, we actually
have to groom the hair,
we have to model that shape, and for Spot,
it was an interesting
challenge because his hair
is so tangled it becomes
a very important thing
to make sure those hairs aren't
intersecting in weird ways
and that you can feel that
the hairs are actually
twisting around one another,
in order to do that,
we ended up using a
technique that was developed
at Disney Animation where
we're using geometric tubes
to shape gross shapes in his hair,
so that you can really get the appeal
of individual clumps of hair,
and see how it tapers along
towards the end of the
hair, so with those tubes,
once they're shaped in a certain way,
we fill those tubes with
curves, and those are the curves
that we end up simulating
as we go forward.
- Now that you had the
shape that you wanted,
how did you set up the
hair simulation to get
the look that you wanted?
- The sim of the hair for him is obviously
a little bit different as
well because you've got this
mangled mass of hair, it
needs to hold that shape,
and it doesn't move like
even your hair would
or someone with straighter
hair, so it doesn't hang
with gravity like you would
think, as a whole for Spot,
his hair is a little tighter
than most of our hair,
the springs are a little bit
tighter so that you don't
get quite as much sag
and it really does feel
like it's been teased and
frazzled and kind of holds up
and defies gravity a little
bit more than natural
like longer hair would be.
- [Interviewer] So Spot
had variation for his hair.
Like when he was wet, so how
were you able to do that?
- Because he was in the
wilderness and we knew
there was a bunch of weather
changes where sometimes
it's starting to rain,
sometimes it's in the middle
of the rain where it's getting heavier,
and sometimes he's soaking wet
'cause he gets in the river,
my colleague David Liley and
I worked on something to where
we started thinking
hey, wouldn't it be cool
if we just changed simulation
parameters to get the hair
that he started with to
be the hair as it changes.
And so he started on the
soaked version of the groom,
and by changing things like
the stiffness of the springs
we could lose that groomed
shape that was all spirally,
it would make it kind of flattened out,
we would turn up the
gravity so that it hanged
a little bit tighter to his face.
So what that allowed us to
do was change the simulation
parameters a little bit at a time,
so maybe gravity would
get a little bit stronger
or the springs would
get a little bit looser,
so that you can get a
variation of that transition
from dry to wet, but you had
various stages in the middle
that you could get which
normally if we were just doing
independent grooms, we
would have more of this kind
of on and off switch, of
like, it's dry, it's wet,
now we can get a nice
blend through that range.
- That's pretty cool,
thanks Jacob for coming by.
And now onto lesson two. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox