PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(metal clattering)
- Now that you are comfortable
with how springs expand and contract,
we can try something a
little bit different.
Let's try connecting a bunch
of springs together like this.
When we simulate springs,
we don't draw them using
the zigzag pattern.
Instead we use lines,
which can expand and contract.
This gives us a really
bouncy strand of hair,
but it's a bit too bouncy.
Notice the hairs take a really
long time to settle down.
This isn't very realistic.
Take a look at our reference shots again.
See how quickly the hairs come to rest,
just a few bounces.
You might think changing the
spring stiffness will fix this,
but look what happens.
Both low and high stiffness values
still result in hair
which never settles down.
Our solution to this is adding
what's called a damper to each spring.
A damper is something that resists
fast changes in displacement,
and it's used to bring springs
to rest much more quickly.
Check this out.
Here we have the same
strand of hair as before,
except each spring is
connected to a damper,
and we can change the amount of dampening
using this new parameter.
If we increase damping,
the springs resist quick changes,
and therefore come to rest much faster.
However, too much damping will result
in really stiff hair,
which isn't natural,
and here's what it looks like
with a whole bunch of hair.
We went through a similar exercise
in the early stages of
modeling Merida's hair.
We were trying to get the right mixture
of spring stiffnesses and damping
so that we could achieve
the desired artistic look,
but with the wrong settings,
the springs start fighting each other,
and you get pretty funny results.
So the trick is to find a nice balance
between spring stiffness and damping.
You can try this out in the next exercise.
Here you can control
damping of each spring,
number of hairs,
number of springs per hair,
and spring stiffness.
See if you can come up with something
that behaves a bit more realistically. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox