1
00:00:00,000 --> 00:00:00,000
PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox

2
00:00:00,742 --> 00:00:02,027
Hi, I'm Hayley Iben
大家好，我是Hayley Iben

3
00:00:02,027 --> 00:00:03,993
I'm a software engineer at Pixar.
我是皮克斯的一位码农

4
00:00:03,993 --> 00:00:05,527
I worked on the hair simulator
我的工作是为brave

5
00:00:05,527 --> 00:00:07,516
for the movie, Brave.
做毛发模拟

6
00:00:07,516 --> 00:00:09,752
Hair was a really big deal in Brave.
毛发在这片子里可真是重头戏

7
00:00:09,752 --> 00:00:11,518
It was a symbol of freedom that was intrinsic
因为他是作为我们主角Merida自由天性

8
00:00:11,518 --> 00:00:14,514
to our main character Merida's personality.
的一种象征

9
00:00:14,514 --> 00:00:16,297
And making hair that feels right,
所以必须是狂野 凌乱 随意的

10
00:00:16,297 --> 00:00:18,246
meaning messy, wild and free,
这才符合角色的特征

11
00:00:18,246 --> 00:00:21,013
is a hard thing to do computationally.
这计算起来就很复杂

12
00:00:21,013 --> 00:00:23,501
In our movies, hair is a simulated effect.
在我们的电影里 头发是一个模拟特效

13
00:00:23,501 --> 00:00:26,248
That means no one animates its movement by hand.
也就是说他不是动画生成的

14
00:00:26,248 --> 00:00:28,030
The way it moves is defined by physics
他的运动是由物理去定义的

15
00:00:28,030 --> 00:00:30,314
and programmed into the computer.
然后由程序生成

16
00:00:30,314 --> 00:00:32,535
To figure out what hair simulation should look like,
为了弄清楚它看起来到底应该怎样

17
00:00:32,535 --> 00:00:34,240
we needed to look at real curly hair
我们需要参考真实的卷发

18
00:00:34,240 --> 00:00:35,741
and see how it worked.
然后看看它是怎么运动的

19
00:00:35,741 --> 00:00:37,033
What we found was this.
我们找到的就是这个

20
00:00:37,033 --> 00:00:39,006
Curly hair forms together in locks
卷发汇聚在一起

21
00:00:39,006 --> 00:00:41,232
that reshape themselves when you pull on them,
当你用力拉的时候 他会重新定型

22
00:00:41,232 --> 00:00:42,757
kind of like a spring.
这有点像弹簧

23
00:00:42,757 --> 00:00:44,501
This was great news because springs
这是个很好的发现

24
00:00:44,501 --> 00:00:46,005
can be modeled mathematically,
因为弹簧是可以用已有的数学模型实现的

25
00:00:46,005 --> 00:00:47,508
meaning we can simulate their behavior
这也就意味着我们可以去模拟他们的行为模式了

26
00:00:47,508 --> 00:00:49,949
using a computer program.
使用一种程序

27
00:00:49,949 --> 00:00:51,293
From the computer's perspective,
从电脑的角度

28
00:00:51,293 --> 00:00:53,524
Merida's hair is just lots and lots of springs Merida的头发就是很多很多的弹簧

29
00:00:53,524 --> 00:00:55,765
that react to forces, such as gravity,
当merida运动的时候，头发受到各种力的影响

30
00:00:55,765 --> 00:00:57,468
as Merida moves.
比如重力

31
00:00:57,468 --> 00:01:00,023
The tests we ran using this approach were pretty good,
我们测试的结果很成功

32
00:01:00,023 --> 00:01:01,798
but not quite natural enough.
但还不够自然

33
00:01:01,798 --> 00:01:04,483
While stiffer springs held the shape of the curl,
当较硬的弹簧保持卷曲形的时候

34
00:01:04,483 --> 00:01:06,553
it didn't bounce like natural curls.
它不会自然地弹起

35
00:01:06,553 --> 00:01:08,130
When we made the springs loser,
当我们把弹簧调松候

36
00:01:08,130 --> 00:01:10,498
her curls would unwind when she moved.
当她运动时 头发的卷曲就不再缠绕了

37
00:01:10,498 --> 00:01:12,245
This was even more obvious at high,
这在高速是更明显

38
00:01:12,245 --> 00:01:15,245
often unrealistic speeds, found in animation.
尤其是动画里

39
00:01:15,245 --> 00:01:16,785
We realized we needed something
我们意识到我们需要一些方法

40
00:01:16,785 --> 00:01:18,747
to preserve the structure of the curl,
来保持它的卷曲

41
00:01:18,747 --> 00:01:21,508
but not impede the overall motion of the hair,
但又不能阻止整个头发的动态

42
00:01:21,508 --> 00:01:22,988
kinda like digital hairspray.
就像是数字头发喷剂

43
00:01:22,988 --> 00:01:25,253
(can hissing)
Oh, sorry (laughs).
噢，对不起

44
00:01:25,253 --> 00:01:27,241
We came up with the idea of connecting
我们想出了一个主意来连接

45
00:01:27,241 --> 00:01:29,763
the springs that make up Merida's on-screen hair
组成merida 可见的头发的各个弹簧

46
00:01:29,763 --> 00:01:32,985
to invisible core springs like this.
我们使一些核心弹簧不可见

47
00:01:32,985 --> 00:01:34,522
The core springs would limit the movement
而当运动越来越趋于极限的时候

48
00:01:34,522 --> 00:01:35,555
of the on-screen hair
这些不可见的弹簧

49
00:01:35,555 --> 00:01:37,504
when the motion was more extreme.
将限制可见的头发的运动

50
00:01:37,504 --> 00:01:39,787
This way, we could have the best of both worlds.
这样 我们就两全其美了

51
00:01:39,787 --> 00:01:41,754
Our original simulation we create motion
我们原有的模拟讲形成动态

52
00:01:41,754 --> 00:01:43,480
that was soft and natural,
保持柔软和自然

53
00:01:43,480 --> 00:01:45,105
but the core springs would keep the curl
而核心弹簧可以保持头发的卷曲度

54
00:01:45,105 --> 00:01:47,001
from unwinding too much.
避免头发被快速的运动拉直了

55
00:01:49,001 --> 00:01:51,483
Figuring out how to make a hair simulation system
而做出这个头发的模拟系统

56
00:01:51,483 --> 00:01:53,238
that could help us achieve the feeling we wanted
有助于我们达到我们想要的东西

57
00:01:53,238 --> 00:01:54,768
for Merida's hair was hard.
merida的头发很难

58
00:01:54,768 --> 00:01:57,039
It took a lot of iterations to get it right,
他需要很多迭代算法才能得到正确的结果

59
00:01:57,039 --> 00:01:58,302
but it made a big difference.
但真的会有很大的不同

60
00:01:58,302 --> 00:02:01,067
Merida feels like a real girl,
这样merida看上去就像一个真的女孩一样

61
00:02:01,067 --> 00:02:02,000
messy, wild and free. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
凌乱 狂野而随意
