PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- When I was young, I
really liked some sports
like softball and I was the catcher
and the first base player
and I also liked music.
I started playing the
flute in the fourth grade
and from there I played in the band
and I branched out and
taught myself tenor saxophone
and played that in the jazz band
and I was in the marching
band and the symphonic band
and I was a drum major
and lots of different
activities with music.
It was great.
In high school, there
were some elective classes
that we need to take and my
mom was helping me figure out
which ones to pick.
And she had gone back to
school while I was a kid
and she had taken a programming class
and she suggested that I took one of those
to see if I liked it and
so that's how I got into it
and I already liked computers,
I love playing with them.
I remember my parents
getting our first computer.
It was an old 286
and it was just something that was
at that point a toy but then learning
how to program a computer
was really interesting to me
and so I started taking
computer classes in ninth grade
and all through high school.
Yeah, I majored in computer science
in the liberal arts school
and got a Bachelor of Science
and I also did a minor in mathematics.
I got a Master's and
a PhD from UC Berkeley
and my Master's was in
computational geometry
and my thesis was on
physically-based simulation
for creating crack patterns on
surfaces so like mud drawing.
I also looked at crackle glass
and so that's a way to create
crack patterns in class
and use that for cups and
bowls and things like that.
In my internship,
I ended up working on an
inverse kinematics problem
with Andy Weken who was my
mentor and the research group.
Let's pretend I wanna animate my arm
and I would wanna grab
my wrist and move it here
and what inverse kinematics
does is it would solve
to figure out what are the angles
that I'd have to move my elbow
joint and my shoulder joint
to hit the target which
is where my wrist is.
It's really exciting for me
to watch the finished movie for Brave.
I worked on a lot of the
technology that was used
to animate the characters
and to do the hair simulator.
I wrote the inverse kinematic system
that was used to move the
horses and move the humans.
I spent a lot of time trying to make sure
that posing tool was right and having that
and have Merida's hair
fill up the entire screen
was incredibly satisfying
and to see how beautiful
it all turned out.
And while I was writing those tools,
I got scheduled to do an interview
with another co-worker
for the simulation group
because they were looking
for a new simulation person
and the person who left had done
fluids and other types of simulation work
that wasn't an area
that I was familiar with
so I hadn't even thought about
this work, this job opening
and I think it had been
open for about a year
when we were talking about it.
They were having a hard
time filling this position
and the person we were interviewing
was doing a Master's thesis
and he was implementing
some of my PhD thesis
and so after the interview,
my co-worker said,
he turned to me and said,
"Why aren't you applying for this job?"
That was really a point in my career
to really sit and think like,
"Huh, why I aren't I
applying for this job?"
And so I really gave it some
consideration and decided
and was like, "Yeah, I do
wanna apply for this job."
And it's always a little
bit scary when you try to
do something new but it
was definitely worth it.
I didn't listen to the
people that were saying,
"Oh, you should be doing this instead,"
because you should do
what your heart tells you
and even if it's scary, you
should go ahead and do it. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox