PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(jumping, bouncing)
(light switches on)
- Great work.
So far we've built up a model of hair
using a series of damped springs.
This gives us a more realistic behavior,
like this style I came up with.
But remember, the art department
wants Merida's hair to be curly.
Sometimes it curls up while moving but it doesn't
hold that curly shape while at rest.
Here's an idea.
What if we put some smaller springs in between
the larger springs to pull them together?
Let's call them support springs.
We already have a mathematical model of the spring
so this is easy to test out.
If I connect a support spring between the larger
springs, I get something like this.
If I hide the support springs, you'll notice the hair
comes to a rest in a curly shape.
That's much better.
Adding these support springs results
in new parameters we can control.
The stiffness and length of the support springs.
Shorter support springs will give us smaller curls,
while really long support springs give us bigger ones.
And if we make the support springs have a higher stiffness
the curl pops up like this.
Kind of like we applied hairspray.
Compare this to support springs with lower stiffness.
In this case, the curls relax a bit
and fall downwards in a natural way.
Now, let's try this with a bunch of hairs.
Now that's starting to look more like Merida.
This isn't exactly the method we used on Merida
for the movie, but it's close.
In this next interactive you can try this out
with all the parameters we've introduced.
The two new parameters are support spring stiffness
and support spring length.
See what you can come up with. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox