PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- We actually do a lot
of simulation at Pixar.
Things like fire, water, and explosions
are handled by the effects department.
You can learn more about
that in the effects lesson.
The simulation department,
who I work with,
handles any motion attached
to the characters at Pixar,
like clothing and hair.
But we can't move every hair
on a Pixar character's head by hand,
that would drive our animators crazy.
Instead, we use Physics
and Computer Programming.
In this lesson, you'll learn how to
simulate hair the same
way we did for Merida
in the movie "Brave".
Here is an example of a shot of Merida
that the simulation department got
from the animation department
on the film "Brave".
The animators have created
the main action in the scene
and now it's our job to
fill in the missing details
such as the motion of cloth and hair.
Everything we do begins
with modeling the problem
we want to solve.
In this case, we need a physical model
of Merida's curly hair.
So let's begin with the very basics.
What should our model of hair look like?
Well, hair is kind of like a mop,
just a bunch of strings.
But strings are actually quite complex
to model mathematically
because they are so bendy.
Modeling them requires a
lot of computational power
due to all the calculations involved.
This is why we are always looking for ways
to simplify our models.
For example, we could take
a bunch of paper clips
to model a strand of hair.
We first draw a series of line segments
connected to particles, like this.
The computer needs to
calculate the positions
of these particles.
But first we need to describe what forces
are acting on them.
In the real world, each
particle is affected
by three forces.
The force of gravity,
and the forces from neighboring
connections, like this.
Next step, I have an interactive program
for you to see this in action.
You can adjust the following parameters:
size of each segment,
number of segments per hair,
number of hairs, and the force of gravity.
Explore these parameters to see what kinds
of looks you can come up with.
Have fun. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox