PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(bouncing)
- In the last video, we saw this preview
of a shot from Finding Nemo
where we've drawn the particles as balls
to illustrate their motion.
For the final shot, we
used the particle positions
to compute a surface.
Then we rendered that surface
to look more like water.
To draw a smooth surface
using individual particles,
we use an analogy involving heat.
First, imagine these
particles are little heaters.
Next, pretend we have a thermometer
which tells us the temperature
at any point in space.
For example, the particles
might be exactly 1,000 degrees,
and as we move away, things cooled down.
Let's say this point over
here is exactly 100 degrees,
and there isn't just one point in space
which is 100 degrees, but many points.
So if we connect all points
where the thermometer
says 100 degrees, we get a
curve shown here in yellow.
And that's the trick.
Now we can fill in this yellow
curve with a solid blue color
to give us something that looks
more like a puddle of water.
If the particles are far apart,
they each form their own
isolated region, like a droplet.
As they get closer, the
droplets start to glob together,
mimicking real water.
Here's a version with
a few more particles.
This is starting to look like water.
It would really look like water
if we had a few thousand particles.
For use in our movies, we
work in three dimensions,
and the curve becomes a surface
like in this shot from Finding Dory,
or in this more extreme water simulation
also from Finding Dory.
Here's an example from
Monsters University.
Here we're simulating
paint, instead of water.
We've turned up the viscosity
since paint is more viscous than water.
We weren't exactly sure
how paint would behave
so one of the first things
we did to create this shot
is to videotape reference of real paint.
The reference really helped
us create a believable look.
Let's pause here so you can practice
using the next exercise.
Good luck.
(playful music) aimozhen.com/pixarinabox