PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Hi, I'm Matt Wong, an Effects Technical Director
here at Pixar.
I work with Sara Beth and Eric who you met
in the previous video and this is the pool they were in,
the Pixar Pool, which is one of the nice perks
of working here at Pixar.
We don't just use the pool for recreation,
we sometimes use it for work, too
like in this reference video we shot for Finding Dory.
We wanted to see what it would look like underwater
when large objects like this pumpkin hit the water.
In the previous video you learned that water
and other physically phenomena like smoke, dust,
and fire can be simulated using lots and lots
of individual particles.
Using particles is a simplification of real physics
but it's an effective tool for artists.
The more particles you use
the closer you get to real physics.
Most of our simulations require millions and millions
of particles to create believable water.
Keeping track of that many particles would take too long
for humans to do.
Even computers have trouble with large particle counts
but we've developed some practical methods
that you'll learn about in this lesson.
One of the most power techniques we use
is called a particle system.
Particle systems were first invented by an effects artist
named Bill Reeves to create a shot for the movie
Start Trek Two back in 1982.
The shot was called the Genesis Effect
and it blew people away.
It was a real milestone in computer graphics.
At the time Bill was working for a group
that eventually became Pixar.
And you know what, he still works here.
Hey Bill.
- Hey.
- Can you tell us a little bit more
about the Genesis Effect?
Like what was the story point?
- Well the Genesis Effect was this device
that could turn a living planet into a dead planet
or a dead planet into a living planet and I used
particle systems to do the transformational fire element
at that.
- And today we still use particles
for lots of different effects.
In the rest of the lesson you'll learn how we use particles
to simulate the motion of water
and you'll create a fireworks show. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox