PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
Hello! I'm Eric and I am an effects artist at Pixar.
And I'm Sara Beth, another Pixar effects artist.
Pixar called "effects" to the creation and animation of anything that moves
but that is not a character.
Almost all natural phenomena in our films are created by teams of effects.
Things like dust
(cough)
Smoke!
Fire
(cough)
explosions
ATTORNEY PIXAR
Do not
(Sound of explosion)
and effects created water is its different forms.
Computer make credible water is very exciting and a challenge
this is partly because water takes many forms:
the placid lake where you can swim,
or pounding river would not want to catch you.
The type of water we create depends on the story we want to tell
and how we approach the water is different depending on how you interact with characters
and how close we are to them.
One of the tools we use to create believable water on the computer are particles.
We begin with a single particle.
We can apply forces to the particle such as wind or gravity
or more particles that push and pull each other.
Adding many, many, many more particles
and applying those same forces
water started to create on the computer.
The water in the real world is also made of particles
because the molecules are just tiny particles
and although our particles are much, much larger than the molecules
physics is similar, so we simulate
those forces using real world math and code.
It takes years and years to encourage individually
the millions of particles that make water into scenes,
so it helps that we can use an existing set of rules
they can follow the particles on the computer.
You might be probably wondering how I can make water for animated films.
Sara Beth Good question!
In the following lessons you will learn all about how to create particles and water using simulation.
Have fun and remain dry!  aimozhen.com/pixarinabox