PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Okay, now that you're
comfortable with this diagram,
I think you are,
we can develop our final formula.
Remember, we need a formula that tells us
what BC is in terms of things we know,
like the focal length of the lens,
the size of the aperture, and
the distance to our object, P.
The key to this formula is to notice that
there are similar triangles
lurking in the diagram.
To figure this out, let's
simplify our diagram
to show only the two
triangles we care about.
Notice the triangle ABC is
similar to the triangle AED.
That means that the length BC divided by
the length DE is equal to
the length AB divided by AE.
Let's call this Equation One.
We know what DE is, that's
the radius of the aperture.
But we don't know AB or AE.
I'm also gonna add two
new points, F and G.
This gives us two new right triangles,
ABF and AEG, which are also similar.
This means that AB divided by
AE equals FA divided by AG.
But, FA is just the difference
between i and i prime,
and AG is the distance i.
So, we can rewrite this
as AB divided by AE
equals i prime minus i, divided by i.
And now, let's substitute
this back into Equation One,
which gives us BC divided by DE equals
i prime minus i, divided by i.
Finally, we just solve for
BC, which gives us our answer.
BC equals DE times i prime
minus i divided by i.
Ah, ha, we have an equation
for the Circle of Confusion.
(chiming)
If you wanted to, you
could also substitute
i and i prime from the
simple lens equation
to write out the radius
of the Circle of Confusion
in terms of F, O, and O prime.
I'll leave that for you to work
out in this final exercise. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox