PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(metal clattering)
- Although our movies
involve hundreds of people
and take years to make,
they all begin with a simple idea
about some world and character.
- What if there's life
out there in the universe?
- What if a rat wanted
to cook haute cuisine?
- What if our toys that, you know,
are all around us actually were sentient
and can come alive?
- These what if questions
invite the imagination
into a story we want to explore.
Let's hear how our story
artists use what ifs.
- So what if questions kind
of really drive that imagination.
- The best what ifs
are questions that sort of,
they feel like a key
that unlocks a door.
- It really shuts down the
logic part of your brain,
and it lets you engage the
dream part of your brain,
and somehow it opens up
the doors to imagination,
or at least for me it does,
and what if sort of seems
to ask this question
to let yourself wonder.
So when it came to writing
and directing Sanjay's Super Team,
the thing that I came to first
was what I wanted to say.
What if we could finally see
what my father was seeing in his mind
with his spirituality and his faith?
What if we could show that with vivid,
three dimensional, Pixar technology
to this little boy who worships cartoons.
That was the big what if
that I challenged the art department with.
- At Pixar, these what
ifs are not only fun,
but they're a simple way
to communicate a story idea
and kick off our entire creative process,
so it's important to be
able to communicate stories
in this concise way.
In the next exercise,
you'll reframe your three favorite films
in terms of what if statements. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox