PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- A What If statement is ultimately connected
to a world and a character.
When we say world, what we really mean
is the environment, or set of rules,
in which our story will take place.
It could be literal, like a coral reef,
or figurative, like the mind of a young girl.
Character, of course, refers to
the subjects or individuals we follow
on the journey of the story.
What if there was one less robot left on Earth?
Let's hear about some of the worlds and characters
that inspired our Pixar story artists.
Star Wars has this great What If question,
which is what if there was a band of rebels
that were trying to be the guardians of the human spirit
and let's say there was this great war that was going on
between this non-feeling technology
trying to wipe out this kind of subtle human feeling
and it just has this great powerful What If question
that really drew me in to that world.
- The great thing about the world of Toy Story
is that it's this really beautiful metaphor
for growing up.
And it's so genius because it's so,
from the outside it looks so simple,
but from the inside it's so complicated
and so beautiful.
So I think that's a really good example
of a world sort of leading the story
and a world containing a metaphor within it
that we can all sort of grasp and hold on to.
- One of my favorite movies is Raising Arizona
by the Coen brothers.
Well, the world takes a backseat
to the character of this protagonist
who wants to sort of steal a baby,
so him and his wife could have this family.
That character is so incredibly alive to me
that he could just stand there on the screen
and it would still be really compelling.
- Personally, I always think character should come first
and then the world comes after.
For example, a blind person forgetting his pants
and going to work will have a completely different story
than a seeing-eyed person forgetting his pants
and going to work.
Two characters will have completely different stories
but all of the objects and the setting
and everything else is completely the same.
So, for me, character is king.
- Everybody works a little differently.
So, for me, I like to come at it from world first
and then find the character to go into this world,
or who that character is going to be.
I needed to set the stage
for a bunch of other characters to go through
and then that was the equation
for stories to come out.
- Sometimes the world comes first
and sometimes the character comes first.
Either way, the story's born when both things,
world and character, meet.
Let's get warmed up in this next exercise,
thinking about characters and worlds
in the stories you love. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox