PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(clicking)
Great work!
Now we've got all the math we
need for a computer program
to draw as many lines as we need
to create a good
approximation to a parabola.
Let's return to some of the
artistic aspects of grass
starting with the width.
In this interactive, I
can move the points around
and I haven't drawn the
legs of the control polygon
just to make it look a little bit simpler
and, let's see,
that kind of shape for the
spine looks pretty good.
So let me move on to the next step
which is to define the width.
I'm going to do that using
something we'll call a Skeleton.
The Skeleton is a set
of lines, like these,
that cut across the blade
of grass at 90 degree angles
so here's a Skeleton line,
here's a Skeleton line
and so on.
If I connect all the left
sides of the Skeleton lines
and the right side of the Skeleton lines,
I create a region, let me fill that in,
and that region looks a lot
more like a blade of grass.
(click)
(tinkling)
I can control the width
using this slider here
so that's just adjusting the
length of those Skeleton lines
and that width there looks pretty good.
Finally, I can control the color.
I can go from a deep green
to a lighter green
to a really light green.
Our artists control parameters like this
to create the kind of convincing grass
that you see in "Brave."
Use this interactive to see what kinds of
blades of grass you can create
and then, in the next video,
we'll talk about how to animate it. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox