PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(lamp and ball boinging)
- Congratulations.
You're now an expert on midpoints.
(arrow whooshes)
Now let's take the next step.
I've been claiming that the curves created
with the string art construction are parabolas.
But how do we know that's actually true?
Well, it's actually a little bit hard to prove that
rigorously but we can get some intuition
in the following exercise.
Now you may have seen parabolic arcs
as graphs of quadratic equations
like this one, for instance.
So here I have a green curve that's the graph
of a quadratic function.
And so it's a parabola.
And I have a blue curve generated through
the string art construction.
It's my job in this exercise,
it'll be your job in the exercise,
to see if you can reposition the points
so that the blue curve sits exactly
on top of the green curve.
So for instance, I'm gonna try moving this point,
say down here.
And this point over here.
Over there.
So the blue curve is getting a little bit closer,
but it's not exactly on top of the green curve yet.
And in fact I'm gonna ask you to try it
in the next exercise. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox