PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Well as a child I grew up
in the age of Apollo, the moon mission.
So I always knew I wanted to go into science.
First I thought I wanted to be
an astronaut like everybody my age.
I didn't really discover mathematics
until I was in 7th grade.
I was building model rockets at the time
and my 7th grade science teacher showed me how
to use trigonometry to calculate
how high the rockets were going.
And I thought that was just so cool that I could, with math,
figure out how high something went
without having to get a big ladder or a ruler.
And then in graduate school I discovered that you could
put math, science, and computers together.
That was computer graphics.
And I was lucky enough to be there really
at the beginning of computer graphics in the early 80s.
So I was hooked immediately.
After graduate school I went to the University of Washington
and started as a professor there,
where I started a computer graphics laboratory.
Stayed there for about 10 years but the computer graphics
community was really small at that time
and everybody knew everybody.
So I really stayed in touch with a lot of people at Pixar.
About 10 years after I got to Washington,
that was about when "Toy Story" was being finished.
And I thought, "Gee, if I'm ever gonna
"try something different, this is a good time."
So I did the unthinkable I left an academic position
and joined this little startup called Pixar.
When I got to Pixar one of the first projects
I got to work on was the short film "Gerri's Game".
Which was really exciting because it was a chance
to take some of the technology I'd been working on
at the University of Washington
and really apply it in the film industry.
It was really successful both creatively and technically.
It won an Academy Award for Best Short Film that year.
And later I won an Academy Award for the work
that I did on "Gerri's Game", the technical work.
The technical work I did on "Gerri's Game" is talked
about in the character modelling lesson with Alonzo.
It's the mathematics of sub-division.
So I've done various things at different times
in my almost 20 years at Pixar.
For the last 10 years I've been leading
the computer graphics research group here.
So it's our job to get out in front
of technology needs of future films.
We built a new hair simulator
for Merida in the film "Brave".
More recently in "Inside Out" one of the researchers
Kurt Fleischer developed some new technology
for helping animators get even stronger
performances out of their characters.
Looking ahead over the next five to 10 years
one thing we're working on hard
in the research group is how to make
all these complex calculations go in real time.
That is at least 24 updates per second.
Right now in some areas, including simulation, the updates
can take minutes or hours per frame.
Getting into computer graphics these days
is so much easier then when I was a kid.
In fact, when I was a kid,
computer graphics didn't really exist.
These days if you're interested in computer graphics
there are lots of opportunities online.
You can go to Blender dot org for instance,
download a free software package that does
animation very much like the tools that we use in-house.
It's free, there are lots of great tutorials.
Using Blender you can get an idea
of how the artists here at Pixar work.
And then using Pixar in a Box you can
understand some of the mathematics that Blender requires.
Well for fun for the last 10 years or so
my two sons and I, in fact our whole family,
have been building kind of wacky projects
to take to this big event every year
in the Bay area called Maker Faire.
In 2010 for instance we built and eight and a half foot tall
animatronic fire breathing dragon.
Why not, right?
In 2012 we built a flight-simulator based on
the TV show "Battlestar Galactica".
And just this past year we took a powered exoskeleton,
kind of inspired by movies like
"Elysium" and "Edge of Tomorrow."
In those films the exoskeletons are props
and we wondered, "Hmm, could we build one
"of these things that actually really works?"
So my youngest son brought together seven of his friends
and we took something to the faire
that really put a lot of smiles on people's faces. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox