PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
Hi, my name is Inigo Quilez
I'm working on Brave,
creating forests, trees and the environment as a whole in the film
and I use a lot of math.
I think most people think of mathematics
as something boring, mechanical, but
at Pixar we do not think so.
For us, math is a tool for creating images, movement, splendor, fun.
This lesson will focus on one of the places where we use mathematics
to create landscapes in Merida fighter.
Let's start with the simplest things you can find in this landscape -
blades of grass.
A blade of grass is something that begins at a point, rising to one side
and bent downward.
It looks like a small, narrow curve.
This is good news because the mathematics
It has a lot of tools to describe curves.
In this case, we chose a parabola,
which is a very specific curve.
The curve gives us, however, only the core,
Besides, we need to have a blade thickness and color.
And to fill the forest, we need to create millions of these curves, and give them
appropriate thicknesses, colors to make them look natural.
Want to know more?
Stay with us to the end of the lesson.  aimozhen.com/pixarinabox