PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- You remember Patrick from the first video in this lesson?
I've invited him here to talk a little bit about camera use.
- Cheese!
- Can you tell us a little bit about
how you use depth of field in storytelling?
- So, the one that has depth of view
is part of the storytelling is a short film
that I worked on called The Blue Umbrella.
When the director, Saschka, approached me about doing
the cinematography, he wants the audience to feel like
they are kinda watching this love story unfold,
in front of their eyes.
So the idea was to try to use a longer lens
so that there's a distance between
the camera to the subject.
It's like when you're in love, you know?
You just don't look at anything else.
You kinda concentrate on the person in front of you.
And that's kind of the feeling we're trying to get.
(happy music)
- In addition to all the other choices you make,
you could also choose
to move the camera during a shot.
Do you ever use that to help tell a story?
- Oh, yeah, camera movement is very important.
For Inside Out, camera movement is a big part
of the camera structure of how the inside world works
and the outside world works.
The inside world is a perfect world?
It's imaginative.
So all the camera movement is very mechanical,
it's very deliberate.
Whenever it's moving you can kinda predict where it's going.
So everything is very formal.
On the outside world, on the other hand, is more organic,
depending on the moments.
So how we move the camera is very, very important.
- And you're also focusing just like with a real camera
to make sure the right things are in focus.
Do you ever use focus as a way of telling a story?
Or the way you focus?
- Yes, actually on Inside Out, we used focus to try to
add to the imperfection of the real world, Riley's world.
Because Riley's world is based on a real location,
San Francisco, Minnesota.
We want the camera, it just feels natural
that the camera should feel real.
And imperfection is part of the real world.
And something about Pixar's focus
is that everything is always so perfect,
because we're inside a computer.
So we purposefully,
in act two and act three especially,
when the cameraman is trying to follow an action,
we purposefully miss some of the focus and then refocus.
It's just some of the subtlety
we're trying to do to try to get to the imperfection.
It's something that hopefully the audience can feel
but not something that they can just say oh, yeah,
I can see what they did.
- Thanks, this is fascinating, thanks for coming by.
- Well, thank you for having me, Adam. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox