PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- When I started college,
computer graphics was a really primitive medium
at that point.
It was plotter graphics
and we had a device at our computer lab
that allowed you to draw a picture
with lines and so that's where I learned
about geometric transformations and linear algebra
and the things that go into CG
because we had this device
and I wanted to draw pictures on it.
When I started at Pixar, I got a summer job
doing what you would now call IT,
which was what we called the Systems Group.
I kept one of the four computers
that we had in the main computer room.
I helped keep it running, and in my off hours,
I got to use the CG lab that had a handful
of image computing devices in it.
Because I was really interested in that,
I had spent more and more time there
and when there was some work to be done in the graphics side
of things, I did that, that was really fun.
I built most of Andy's neighborhood with some help
from some other people who built a few houses.
I created the street and the road
and I dressed the trees in and I worked
with somebody to make the trees renderable.
I also built Scud, the dog.
Scud started as a big sculpture
and sculpey of a big dog
and we had to figure out a way of wrapping a surface,
a CG surface around Scud and making it all kind of connect,
and then articulate, make it move,
get the controls in so the animators could move it,
and then work with another people
to put color on him and fur on him.
I will spend a Saturday taking apart a camera,
taking all the old grease out and making it work again,
maybe making new parts of some of the old ones
that are broken and putting it back together,
or I'll go on a road trip and take pictures
'cause there's nothing better than road trips and cameras. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox