PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- [Narrator] Okay, so far you've
made a single shape object
which contains information
to draw a circle,
but we'll need more shapes
to build our snowman,
and we'll want to store
all of these shapes
inside one data structure,
which represents our snowman model.
One way we can do this is with an array,
where each position in the
array holds one shape object.
In the next exercise, you'll
define an array called
shapes array to do this.
Think of this shapes
array as our entire model.
It has everything the computer needs
to draw all the pieces of the model.
But what about a hat for Nick?
We can't draw that with circles...
That would be crazy!
The short film, Nick Nack,
was made with simple geometric shapes.
One easy way to draw any shape
is to define a series of
points called vertices.
For example, the hat would
need eight vertices like this.
Each of these points
is represented by a pair of coordinates.
And then, the entire
list of these vertices
can be stored in a larger array.
So we'll have an array of arrays
to store any shape we want.
And we'll let another part of the program
actually connect these dots for us.
First up, we have two exercises for you.
In the first exercise,
you'll be creating a shapes array
to hold each of your shape objects.
This will allow you to add
your head and your body.
After that, you'll have a
chance to create any shape,
starting with a classic, black hat.
Have fun! (laughs)
Yay!
Go for it! aimozhen.com/pixarinabox