PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Alright, you finally have a
snowman to start working with.
Now we can get to the real
guts of the rigging software.
We need to define our scale, rotate,
and translate deformers.
To allow you to move your shapes around.
And this is where
functions come into play.
Remember, functions package
a series of operations
or procedures we'll use many times.
Functions are set input which they perform
a set of operations on.
Now, to build any deformer,
we'll need a function
which intercepts two inputs.
First they must intercept
a pair of coordinates
which is the vertex in our shape.
And lay a set of value
which is a magnitude of
transformation you want to apply.
For example, the translate x to full
might intercept a coordinate 2,2.
And for the 2nd input would
provide a value of say five.
And so this translate x function,
the math we'll do is quite simple.
Hey that's five to the x coordinate
which updates it to 7,2
and that's the process for transforming
each vertex into shape.
Of course, a shapes contain many vertices.
For example, a hat has eight.
That means its function
is run eight times.
Once for each vertex.
Order of the deformer
functions transform vertices
using equations.
And the transformation depends
on the types of equations
used in your functions.
The equations used for scaling,
rotate, and translation
are all different from each other.
We cover these equations in detail
in our sets and staging lesson.
In the next code review,
we'll give you an example of
writing a translation function
and then in the exercise,
we'll allow you to write
free deformer functions on your own.
Alright, I'm out of here.
(chuckling) aimozhen.com/pixarinabox