PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Now that you have a feel for how t works,
we're ready to calculate our intersection point I
between our ray CP and our line segment AB.
Recall from the previous video that
the slope intercept form of the line AB
is y equals negative three x plus 11
and the parametric representation of the ray CP
is the function R of t equals one minus t
times C plus t times P.
Different values of the parameter t
locate different points on the ray.
The intersection point that we're after
is one such point on the ray so there
must be some value of t, call it t star,
such that I equals R of t star.
This is really two equations, one for the x-coordinate
of I and one for the y-coordinate.
These two equations are I sub x equals R sub x
of t star, which equals one minus t star
times C sub x plus t star times P sub x.
In the same way I sub y equals R sub y of t star,
which equals one minus t star times C sub y
plus t star times P sub y.
In this particular case C, our camera position,
has coordinates zero, zero
and P has coordinates two, 1/2.
So we have I sub x equals t star times two
and I sub y equals t star times 1/2.
I is also on the line segment AB meaning that
I satisfies the slope intercept form for AB,
that is I sub y equals negative three
times I sub x plus 11.
So we have three equations and three unknowns,
I sub x, I sub y and t star.
We can solve the system of equations
by substituting the first two equations
into the third to get an equation just in t star.
1/2 t star equals negative three
times two times t star plus 11.
Solve this for t star, then plug that value
of t star into the first two equations
to get I sub x and I sub y.
And that's how it's done.
Before we continue get some experience using this
kind of parametric function in the next exercise. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox