PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(introductory sound)
In the previous video,
we've talked about what color a point on a surface is
by considering three factors:
One, how much light falls on the point.
Two, how the surface reflects light,
and three, where the camera is.
For the first factor,
the ray tracer needs to determine
if the point being considered
is visible to the light source.
This is actually pretty easy to answer.
The ray tracer constructs a ray that starts at the point
being shaded and launches off in the direction
of the light source.
These rays to light sources
are called, naturally enough, shadow rays.
Here's an example of an point that is visible
to the light source, because the shadow ray
doesn't hit anything but the light source.
It's important to notice that only some of the light
falling on a point comes directly from the light sources.
This is called direct illumination.
In the real world, some of the light
comes from other objects in the scene as well.
Notice that I can bounce light off this card,
which you can see adds to the light hitting my face.
This is an example of indirect illumination.
As another example of indirect illumination,
you can see a reflection of the tennis ball
in the pool ball.
A ray tracer can account for such reflections
by sending another ray in the reflection direction.
The direction of this reflective ray
is determined by how a light ray would bounce naturally
in the same way a pool ball bounces.
This technique was used, for instance, in Cars 2
because reflections off shiny cars were super important
to the look of the film.
If the object is partially transparent, like this glass cup,
the ray tracer can do a similar thing
and launch a ray in the refracted direction.
Refracted rays pass through an object
while reflected rays bounce off of them.
When the rays pass through an object, such as this glass,
the rays bend in different directions
instead of in straight lines, which explains why
the image you see of me through this glass looks warped.
(ding)
The ray tracer can keep doing this, casting rays,
sending out reflective and refractive rays
to account for reflections, the refractions, and so on.
Then, it uses all of these rays
to determine the final pixel color.
In this next exercise, you can test
your understanding of these concepts. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox