PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- In the previous video
we saw that the basic job of a ray tracer
is to determine what color to paint each pixel.
And it does that by casting a mathematical ray
that starts at the camera,
passes through a pixel,
and then off into the scene.
The ray tracer must then compute
the closest intersection point
between the ray and the scene geometry,
and return that geometry's color.
In this video,
we're gonna look at how we determine
how much light is travelling along the ray
back towards camera.
That's what we need to figure out
in order to determine each pixel's color.
This is actually a pretty deep and complicated question
that is mathematically governed by the rendering equation.
I know it looks scary.
I mean believe me,
this equation still gives me nightmares.
But it's actually easy
if you break it down into a few pieces.
The amount of light travelling from a point
on a surface back to the camera
depends on three things.
One, how much light is falling on that point?
Two. how does the surface of the object
at that point reflect light?
And three, where is the camera?
Let's examine each of these factors in turn
using some props.
My scene consists of a tennis ball
and a light source.
Now, the first factor is
how much light is falling on a spot
on that tennis ball?
It's pretty obvious that the farther away the light,
the lower the intensity of light
falling on the ball.
So, we need to know the distance to the light source
and we need to know how bright the light is.
It's less obvious that we need to take into account
the orientation of the surface
when determining how much light falls on the point.
Grazing angles receive less light or energy,
so they appear less bright.
Whereas the point will be brighter or hotter
if the surface is oriented perpendicular
to the direction of the light.
You feel this every sunny day.
It's why it's hottest at noon
and cooler in the morning and evening.
If there is more than one light source,
we repeat the process for each one of them.
The second factor is
how does the surface reflect light?
The color of an object is a big part
of how it responds to light.
But it's not the only factor.
Some objects have a fuzzy or dull appearance
like the tennis ball.
Others are shiny and display bright highlights
like this pool ball.
These two objects are receiving the same amount of light,
but they look very different.
Other surfaces are somewhere
in between dull and shiny
like human skin, wood, or even hair.
Dull surfaces are said to be diffuse
and shiny surfaces are said to be specular.
Finally, the last factor is
where is the camera?
Watch the middle of the number 3 on the pool ball.
Notice that as we move around,
the brightness of that point changes.
Even though everything else is the same
the only thing changing is the location of the camera.
Let's look at a virtual version of this physical situation.
There are three sliders that you can control.
Spotlight intensity which is like controlling
the brightness of the flashlight.
A diffuse slider which controls
the dullness of the surface or roughness.
And specular slider which controls the shininess.
You can also move the spotlight around
which is represented by a white dot.
For every object in a Pixar movie
there's a shader packet.
The shader packet describes in visual detail
everything about a surface.
It will include photographs of what something
looks like in real life.
Drawings describing may be the way
the roughness on a surface looks
or how someone's hair should look.
In this next exercise,
you can sit in the seat of an artist
using tools based on these concepts
we just covered.
Your job as a Pixar artist
is to match the reference art.
Have fun. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox