PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(springing noises)
- We're a good way towards building a shot
that matches the sketch we got from the story department.
But before we continue, let's pause for a moment
to explore an interesting issue that comes up
when combining operations.
In the last exercise, you used the two operations
of scaling and translation to position some objects.
For example, suppose I start by translating this object
by five in X and three in Y,
and then scale by a factor of two.
But what if I change the order
and do scaling before translation?
In this case, I'll scale by a factor of two,
and then translate by five in X and three in Y.
Huh. I get a different result.
^ That means the order of operations matters
^ when we combine scaling and translation.
Let's try applying two different translations.
The first by, say, hmm, five in X and three in Y.
And the second by, say, two in X and four in Y.
And if I do these in the opposite order,
I get the same result.
^ So apparently, order doesn't matter
^ when combining two translations.
When order doesn't matter, mathematicians say
that the operations are commutative.
(magical chiming)
When order does matter, mathematicians say
the operations are (magical chiming) non-commutative.
Translations commute with each other
because addition is commutative.
^ But scaling and translation don't commute.
^ We'll study commutativity in more detail a little later.
In the meantime, use the next exercise
to get some practice with this concept. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox