PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Hi, I'm Fran, a technical director
here at Pixar Animation Studios.
I'm talking to you today from the lobby
of one of the beautiful buildings of the Pixar campus.
As we learned in the previous video,
when we create shots to make up our movies
we need to assemble the environment
where the story takes place.
If I were to build this kind of environment,
I'd start by placing the really big forms
like the walls and the floor.
Then I'd place the dramatic elements
like this gargantuan fireplace behind me.
Then I'd move down to the medium sized elements
and do selection and placement of the couches,
tables and chairs.
Finally, I'd move down to the really small details
like the magazines on the table
and the pieces of wood in the fireplace.
All of these items need to be positioned
using the mathematical operation of translation,
properly sized using the scaling operation
and oriented using rotations.
These operations are all examples of
fundamental geometric transformations.
We'll spend the remainder of this lesson
looking more closely at them.
For our films, these transformations control
what's going on in a virtual three-dimensional space.
^Meaning that each point has three coordinates,
^X, Y and Z.
^But for this lesson we're gonna simplify a bit
and look at laying out floor plans in two dimensions,
like we're viewing them from above.
^So points need only two coordinates, X and Y.
^The X coordinate says how far to the right a point is,
^and the Y coordinate says how far up it is.
^This point for instance has X coordinate three
^and Y coordinate five.
^Before we begin building our own shot from Toy Story,
^let's review how to plot points in 2D
using the next exercise. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox