PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
(techno music)
- To hit our design goal given to us
from the story department,
we'll also have to resize objects in our scene.
For example, I can put Buzz into the shot,
but he's clearly not the size indicated in the sketch.
We can change the size of Buzz, say making
him twice as big by using the scaling operation.
To scale the object to twice its initial size,
I have to multiply the coordinates of each point
in the object by a factor of two.
As before with translation, I can pick any initial point.
Call its coordinates x0 and y0.
After scaling it becomes a point x1 y1.
This formula shows that the coordinates
of each point gets multiplied by two.
More generally, making something s times
as big means multiplying by s.
If s is larger than one, things get bigger.
And if s is less than one, but still positive,
things get smaller.
We can summarize this by saying that the
mathematics of scaling is multiplication.
If the scaling factor in x is bigger than the one in y,
I stretch the object out horizontally.
Think about what would happen if
the y factor is bigger than x.
Also, think about what would happen if s is negative.
We generally need to both scale and translate
objects to put them where we want.
I've already scaled the Luxoball so I
can position it using translation.
Again, as I click on an initial position,
you can see where that point goes
once it's gone through both operations.
The formulas tell us that two operations
are being performed.
In this next exercise, your assignment
is to add to the shot you created in the last exercise
by adding objects that require both
translation and scaling operations.
Remember if they require rotation,
you shouldn't place them in the shot just yet.
(strong drum beat)
Take your time, but honestly the
animation department has been waiting
for this shot for like two weeks.
So, see you in 10 minutes. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox