PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
I looked into the lens. It's matter?
WHY COMPUTER GRAPHICS? How I came to Pixar?
Growing up, I was constantly drawing and painting.
Dad worked at IBM, so the house were computers ...
I remember when brother said:
"Look! The computer can draw."
I was like, "Ooooh! It can be good fun."
When I was little, my dad took me to IBM
a lecture by John Lasseter of computer animation.
Me speechless!
For the first time he showed Luxo Jr. - at least to us.
Zgniatał Luxo before you leap
and extended after landing.
How did you start?
I went to college information
and finished a course of visual arts.
The program concerned the arts, not graphics,
so nobody taught me animation.
She was a computer room in which little happened.
There have prepared their animated film.
SPATIAL FRAME
Well, just take a hat.
In high school I spent a lot of time learning math
and computer science in conjunction with animation,
but most I learned on the job.  aimozhen.com/pixarinabox