PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- In the previous lesson, we focused
on the geometry of dinosaur skins and scales.
- (Blonde Woman) And we used voronoi diagrams
to get the overall structure we were looking for.
- (Brunette Woman) But we simplified a shading
of our skin using only two solid colors with no texture.
- This is why our final result
wasn't very realistic.
We ignored the finer details we see in actual skin.
When you look at your own skin,
do you see one color?
- No, I see a subtle variation in color and texture.
- (Blonde Woman) This variation
becomes really clear when we look
at things under different magnifications or resolutions.
Here's an image of human skin at a very high resolution.
- (Brunette Woman) Wow, it reveals
a whole new world of texture and color variation.
There's nothing smooth or solid about this.
- (Blonde Woman) Right, and because we see
different patterns at different resolutions,
we say that natural surfaces have
a multiresolution structure.
- (Brunette Woman) Let's do another example of this.
- (Blonde Woman) In our shading packet,
we have an image of a Maximo alligator
as reference for our dino scales.
Here's what we see at low resolution.
The skin looks very bumpy and the color's interesting.
- (Brunette Woman) Notice the checkerboard pattern
across the scales, and within each scale
the color looks fairly solid.
- (Blonde Woman) Let's zoom in to a higher resolution.
Here we see smaller scales
which look quite smooth and rounded.
- (Brunette Woman) And notice there's much more
color variation that we didn't see before.
It looks like a speckling of color
due to natural pigmentation as well as dirt.
- (Blonde Woman) Another reference
for our dino skin is snake skin.
At this low resolution it looks like
a collection of solid white and black scales.
- (Brunette Woman) But at higher resolutions
we see new color details.
The white scales contain tiny brown dots
and the black scales have
a light coloration around the edges.
- (Blonde Woman) And if we keep zooming in
things get (laughs) really crazy.
- (Brunette Woman) Aggh! That's scary!
(laughs)
It seems like the closer you look, the more you find.
- Exactly, and that's the essence
of multiresolution structures.
The color and texture of an object
is the result of adding all
of the different details together.
- Before applying these different ideas
to our dino skin, let's pause
for a moment and get you comfortable
look at the world at different resolutions.
- In the next exercise, we'll challenge you
to identify surfaces at different resolutions.
And remember, things aren't always what they seem.
What's your favorite example of something you worked
on that had a really interesting mix of patterns?
- For The Good Dinosaur, on the pterodactyls,
each part of their body had a bunch
of different textures like the crest
had this brain-like texture,
it was kind of icky (laughs) and gross,
and then the neck we used almost like a
dried lava texture to give that feeling of wrinkles.
On the wings we based it on elephant skin
so it would be kind of softer.
And then the body was more like a dry skin feeling,
almost like E.T. phone home (laughs)
kind of feel to it.
It was pretty nice.
It all came back together and we used
different illumination techniques
to make it feel more interesting.
But we used quite a few textures
to mix and match and kind of flow
from one part of the body to the other.
- Pretty cool.
- It turned out okay.
(laughs) aimozhen.com/pixarinabox