PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- Great work.
So far we define a curve which captures
the overall variation and brightness.
- The brightness depends
on the Y coordinate
or amplitude of a curve.
- But remember our goal is to capture
the patterns at different resolutions.
The first curve only captures variation
at low resolutions, think of it as
a broad stroke.
- [Lady Voiceover] So we need to add
higher resolution variation to our curve.
These are the smaller details
or changes in the amplitude.
- [Lady Voiceover] To do this, simply add
two curves together,
for example, take your
original curve and add
it to the second curve,
which would result in this final curve.
- [Lady Voiceover] Very cool.
Mathematically we are just adding
the Y coordinates together.
- [Lady Voiceover] Okay, we've updated
our program so that we can try this out.
At the top is the low resolution curve,
same as the previous exercise.
- [Lady Voiceover] And below it is
a new curve which is created by squishing
two copies of the original curve together.
It's a higher resolution curve
because it contains more detail.
Call this our medium resolution curve.
- [Lady Voiceover] And
we can keep doing this.
Here we've added a third curve.
It's defined by squishing two copies
of the medium resolution curve together
in the same way.
- [Lady Voiceover] This is
our high resolution curve.
It contains the most detailed variations.
- [Lady Voiceover] And
at the bottom we show
the results of adding
these curves together.
- [Lady Voiceover] I
see you have amplitude
sliders as well, that's fancy.
- [Lady Voiceover] Yes, this allows you
to adjust how much that
resolution contributes
to the final curve.
- [Lady Voiceover] Meaning
if the amplitude slider
is set to zero, then that
resolution is ignored
in the final curve, and if I ramp up
it really takes over.
- [Lady Voiceover] By
the way, this process was
invented by Ken Perlin
in 1988 and this is why
the variation is called Perlin Noise.
- [Lady Voiceover] His idea has been used
in almost every computer generated movie
in the past 20 years.
- Now it's your turn to try this out.
In the next exercise we
will test your understanding
of these multi resolution curves.
- Then we can move into higher dimensions.
- Do you have an anecdote
about Perlin Noise?
- Well in addition to surface shading
we all see as noise patterns to control
our hair grooms.
For example you use perlin and other types
of noises to control the length of hairs,
the width, the scraggle, comfing
and other parameters.
You can see it in almost
all of our hair grooms,
definitely Spot's hair
is a good one to look at
for that in The Good Dinosaur.
- [Lady Voiceover] Pretty neat. aimozhen.com/pixarinabox