PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- In the previous exercise you created
2D Perlin noise at a single resolution.
- But remember, our goal is multiresolution variation.
Earlier we did this by adding 2D curves together.
- [Lady Voiceover] Which means we can add
surfaces together in the exact same way.
- [Lady Voiceover] For example, imagine
I took this surface and added it to this surface.
It would result in this final surface.
- [Lady Voiceover] We put together this tool to demonstrate
how we blend 2D patterns at different resolutions.
Let's start with a simple checkerboard example.
Here is a low resolution, a medium resolution
and a high resolution pattern.
This is the result of blending these together.
- [Lady Voiceover] And I see you've added
amplitude sliders to define how much
each resolution contributes to the final result.
- [Lady Voiceover] Yes, exactly as before.
You can adjust the base color too.
- [Lady Voiceover] Very nice.
Let's switch from this checkerboard to the random
patterns used in the previous exercise.
- [Lady Voiceover] Now we have the power to create
a whole range of different results, in fact,
I think we're ready to put this to work in our dino leg.
- Let's do it.
The final program extends what we did
in the previous lesson.
It generates a voanoy diagram as before,
however now we can define the pattern
applied to the skin and scales separately.
- [Lady Voiceover] Oh, fun.
Let me do a quick example.
In this main panel, I can adjust the scale size
as well as manually add and delete sides.
We covered this in our first lesson.
- [Lady Voiceover] Now jump over to the skin controls.
Here you can adjust the base color
as well as the brightness.
Here we have three sliders, one to adjust
the amplitude of the low resolution pattern,
one for medium resolution and one for high resolution.
- [Lady Voiceover] So there's a lot to play with
here to get the look we need.
- [Lady Voiceover] And the scale controls work the same way,
allowing you to create an entirely separate look
for the scales versus the skin.
- [Lady Voiceover] Notice we have two base colors
to select from here, color one defines the color
of the smaller scales, and color two defines
the color of the larger scales.
So any given scale will take on a color
in between your base colors.
- [Lady Voiceover] We did the same thing
in the previous lesson.
This will allow us to get some natural color
variations between the yellow and green Teah
had indicated in her reference arc.
- [Lady Voiceover] Exactly, and when
you're ready to test out your pattern
you can click here, Render in 3D.
It will wrap your pattern around a simple
leg to give you an idea of the finished look.
- Looking pretty good already.
Okay, we better stop here.
Now it's your turn to take over these controls
and create some of your own dino skin
using,
drum roll please,
(drum roll)
- See if you can match Teah's reference art
but then go wild and see what else you can come up with.
- What kind of things do you think about
when you're designing skin for characters?
- Well we think about a lot of different things
but when you're looking at the bumpiness
of each of the cells we felt like
if we were using a curve that was flatter
it gave the skin more of a look like it was
being used more in a harder surface
and therefore, it was an older character
and having the cells be more round, it felt like
it was a younger and fresher feeling skin.
We ended up in the actual skin packet, we used
a ramp from the center of the cell to the edge
of the cell and then we defined what
the curve was because we noticed that it
made such a big difference between having
that flat surface and the rounder curve.
- Interesting.
- So we were actually able to mathematically
define the curve itself with just the patterns
that we had inside each of the cells.
- That's really cool.
- Yeah (laughs). aimozhen.com/pixarinabox