PIXAR IN A BOX 艾墨镇 aimozhen.com/pixarinabox
- So far we've been working with
Perlin noise in one dimension.
- But remember, the problem we really
wanna solve is in two dimensions.
- Luckily, we can apply
the exact same idea in 2D.
This part is really fun.
- [Woman 2] Remember, to
generate 1D variation,
we used a 2D curve to define the variation
of the base color along the line.
- [Woman 1] We used the
x component of the curve
to define the horizontal pixel position,
and the y component defined
the brightness of each pixel.
- [Woman 2] But to make 2D noise,
we'll need to start with a 3D surface
to define the variation across the plane.
Think of a 3D surface as
a collection of points
which have an x, y, and z component.
For example, here is a surface defined
by a bunch of random points.
- [Woman 1] Think about the x and y
coordinates of each point as the finding
the pixel position in a 2D
plane, and the z coordinate
will define the brightness of each pixel.
- [Woman 2] If we do that, we get
a 2D output which looks like this.
Notice the peaks of this surface result
in lighter points, and
the valleys are darker.
- [Woman 1] As before,
the output has very sharp
boundaries between light and dark areas.
That's because the surface isn't smooth.
- [Woman 2] Luckily we
can subdivide this surface
in the exact same way we
smoothed our 2D curve.
This will add new in-between
points to our surface,
resulting in smoother transitions.
- [Woman 1] And that gives us this
very natural looking variation.
It's exactly the kind of cloudy pattern
identified in the shading packet.
- You probably wanna try
this out for yourself.
In the next exercise,
you can try matching some
2D patterns using this technique.
- [Woman 1] We will give
you a target pattern,
and you can match this by
adjusting one the base color.
Two the resolution, this is how far
we zoom in or out of our surface.
Three, the subdivision, or how much
smoothing we apply to the curve.
- In this example we're manipulating
a few parameters to get our look.
But in a real production shading project,
how many parameters would you adjust?
- Well, background
characters would actually
be usually in the hundreds
but main characters,
like Arlo, you would have up to thousands.
If he's in mud, you would control
how much mud he gets,
or the color of the mud,
or how dry the mud is supposed to be.
He could have rain, and so you would
control maybe how fast it is,
or the different parts where
you want the rain to show up.
He could have bruises,
like throughout the journey
he gets bruises and he gets part of
the journey represented on his body.
And you would have controls
for all of those things,
besides colors or maybe
in certain environments
he looks a little bit
too shiny so you want to
bring the shininess down,
or things like that.
So there's just controls
for pretty much everything.
- [Woman 2] Sounds complicated.
- [Woman 1] It is! aimozhen.com/pixarinabox